It was supposed to be the safest room in the house.
Panic Room is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by David Fincher.
Trapped in their New York brownstone's panic room, a hidden chamber built as a sanctuary in the event of break-ins, newly divorced Meg Altman and her
young daughter Sarah play a deadly game of cat-and-mouse with three intruders - Burnham, Raoul and Junior - during a brutal home invasion.
But the room itself is the focal point because what
the intruders really want is inside it.
Meg Altman, played by Jodie Foster.
Sarah Altman, played by Kristen Stewart.
Burnham, played by Forest Whitaker.
Raoul, played by Dwight Yoakam.
Junior, played by Jared Leto.
Stephen Altman, played by Patrick Bauchau.
Panic Room is a 2002 American thriller film directed by David Fincher.
The film stars Jodie Foster and Kristen Stewart as a mother and daughter whose new home is
invaded by burglars, played by Forest Whitaker, Jared Leto, and Dwight Yoakam.
The script was written by David Koepp, whose screenplay was
inspired by news coverage in 2000 about panic rooms.
The film was Fincher's fifth feature film, following Fight Club (1999).
Fincher and Koepp brought together a crew of people
with whom each had worked with before.
The house and its panic room were built on a Raleigh Studios lot.
Nicole Kidman was originally cast as the mother, but she
left after aggravating a previous injury.
Her departure threatened the completion of the film,
but Foster quickly replaced Kidman.
The filmmakers used computer-generated imagery to create the illusion
of the film camera moving through the house's rooms.
Foster became pregnant during the shooting schedule, so
filming was suspended until after she gave birth.
The film's production cost $48 million.
The film was commercially released in the United States and
Canada on March 29, 2002 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film grossed $30 million on its opening weekend.
In the United States and Canada, it grossed $96.4 million.
In other territories, it grossed $100.7 million for a
worldwide total of $197.1 million.
The film was positively reviewed by critics, who commended
Fincher's direction and Foster's performance.
The film explores themes of new york city, hostage, bravery, ex husband, safe.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.